<Document>
  # Server Rules
 ## Rule 0: The Spirit of the Rules
 
* 0.1 - The rules are to be enforced as intended, not literally written.

* 0.2 - Staff reserves the right to enforce rules at their discretion. They should only be doing this for the benefit of the server, the playerbase, or those involved. If there is an aggrieved party, they must always be enforced.

* 0.3 - If you believe staff has improperly enforced rulings, failed to have stopped where it would have been beneficial, or made an incorrect judgment call, you have the right to file a staff grievance, up to the Head of Staff.

* 0.4 - Players deserve the ability to learn and grow alongside staff, and every attempt will be made internally before excluding a player from our space.

 ## Rule 1: Community Conduct
 
* 1.1 - Treat all members with respect and courtesy. Toxicity, harassment, and impersonation of others are explicitly forbidden, along with bigoted content and offensive language.

* 1.2 - Harassment and personal attacks, especially such as defamation or doxxing will be met with removal from our community.

* 1.3 - Promotion or distribution of illegal and illicit content in our community is forbidden.

* 1.4 - Avoid advertising content unless explicitly approved by staff.

* 1.5 - Do not post or discuss recent events OOCly (including in the Discord) unless you have staff approval, or it is considered "public" or "general" knowledge from a large-scale event and after 48 hours


* 1.6 - Metacommunications (talking about the game, outside the game) is strictly against the rules, and metagroups (plotting collaboratively without roleplay outside the game) will be dealt with harshly.

 ## Rule 2: Roleplay
 
* 2.1 - Erotic Roleplay (ERP) is prohibited. No one should be engaging in sexual acts, or behavior, in-game, nor be leaving the platform to do it elsewhere. This applies to any literature or media in-game.

* 2.2 - Persistence SS14 is a High Roleplay (HRP) server that aims to form a long-term storytelling environment, and players should not compromise the entire atmosphere in order to succeed in all personal goals, at all costs.

* 2.3 - Characters must be appropriate, and fit the setting through names, common sense (do not actively seek out pain or death) outside of proper roleplay circumstances, should not be needlessly suicidal, should seek comfort and care (should not be emotionally attached to your voidsuit). Generally, make efforts to eat quality food, engage with the people around them, and be an actual person.

* 2.4 - Roleplay cannot be used an excuse to needlessly murder or grief. Your character must have reason to attack or kill another individual personally.

* 2.5 - You must escalate when attacking another individual, making your intent clear (such as aiming your weapon at them, or ordering them to halt in pursuit) and giving them a chance to respond (them unholstering their weapon, or them continuing to flee). Special circumstances may warrant reduced escalation, such as political assassinations. Request permission from staff prior to obtain this.

* 2.6 - Netspeak is prohibited outside of proper context, such as electronic messaging or non-verbal capabilities.

* 2.7 - Use of metaknowledge that your character would not have access to is forbidden (unless it is "general" knowledge from events after 48 hours). This knowledge can include being a wayfinder around a place they've never been, using event knowledge that was released OOCly but not ICly, or other knowledge that they would have no access to having been shared.
</Document>
